PETER LITTLE

Full-Stack Web Developer

CONTACT



Toronto, ON Canada



thepeterlittle@gmail.com



(289) 404 - 6620



github.com/mysteryhobo

PROFILE

Passionate and dedicated fullstack web developer, with over 3 years experience. Looking for the next challenge in my career.

I'm extremely passionate about two things: self improvement, and building great things so, I'm looking for a small company where I can do both. A company that I can really sink my teeth into, make a big impact, and grow along the way.

My goal is to one day have acquired the skills, knowledge, and experience to run a great company of my own, but, to run a great company, I believe I must first be a part of one. I would love the opportunity to discuss potential positions in your company and how I could be a great addition to your team.

HOBBIES



Programming



Fitness



Self-Improvement



Hockey



Music

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE DEVELOPER / PERSONAL PROJECTS

2019 - Present

Toronto. Ontario

In April 2019 I was scouted and signed by a top modeling and acting agency in Toronto. While working as a model I decided it was the perfect opportunity to explore freelance web development and work on my own projects.

This whole new paradigm of work allowed me to continue to grow my personal skills dealing with freelance clients and their various needs / changing requirements.

Simultaneously, I continued to work every day on my own various sideprojects, pushing my boundaries by learning and implementing new technologies and tools.

Please see page 2 for overview of my projects.

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER / TEAM LEAD

2016 - 2019

360Insights | Whitby, Ontario

Throughout my 3 years at 360Insights, my role continuously grew. My hardwork paid off as I was selected to take over for an outgoing team lead.

As a team lead, I was responsible for facilitating technical discussions, interviewing and onboarding new members, as well as representing my team in cross-team collaborations and meetings with management. My other responsibilities included:

Working within an agile team and CI / CD pipeline to design and build microservices that seamlessly and scalable fit into our application suite.

Collaborating with the UX team for the creation of front-end mock-ups and implementing them with CSS(Less), React, and Redux

Working as a team to build several Node.js backends while utalizing multiple protocols (REST, gRPC, MQTT) to interface with other microservices.

Utilized Jest, Enzyme, and other test utilities to build a comprehensive test suite with 100% coverage while also participating in code reviews to ensure high code quality.

Used several database technologies (MongoDB, MariaDB, MySQL, S3) to suit different storage needs across our platform.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING RESEARCH TECHNICIAN

Summer 2015

University of Ontario Institute of Technology

Responsible for the complete development of a software product including design, implementation, and testing.

See the GameLink project on Pg. 2

EDUCATION

B.ENG. SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

2012 - 2016

University of Ontario Institute of Technology

- Awarded several Dean's List & President's List awards.
- Graduated with honours (3.7 GPA).

PROJECTS

Savvy Price Tracker

Chrome Extension / Web Application

Savvy allows users to quickly track the prices of products for sale on any e-commerce website. Users set a price target opting to be notified via email or push notifications once the product drops to that price.

- React.js Webpack
- Node.js Express
- GraphQL Mongo DB
- AWS (EBS / Lambda)

Landofrhythmos.com

Static Website

Developed for a freelance client, Rhythmos is an upcoming children's musical edutainment company. I was tasked with creating an informative site that demonstrated the creativity and playfulness of the brand.

- Javascript HTML
- CSS(SASS) PHP Gulp
- Bootstrap

Mensfashion.ai

Cloud-based Instagram Bot

@mensfashion.ai is a men's fashion Instagram account run by a cloud-based bot. The bot periodically scrapes Instagram for the best new posts and then automatically re-posts them at scheduled times.

- Node.js Puppeteer
- Google Cloud Functions
- Cloud Scheduler
- Mongo DB React

OutfitFinds.com

Web Application

Outfitfinds.com is a fashion site for Pinterest-esk fashion browsing. Users can browse outfits, discover where to find the pieces of the outfit, and shop for matching accessories using the built-in Shopify store.

- Gatsby.js Netlify
- Puppeteer
- Liquid(Shopify) React
- GraphQL

Toptorial.io

Web Application

Toptorial.io is a web-app designed to allow users to browse and search for top-rated programming books for various languages.

- Node JS React Redux
- Next.js Heroku Redis

GameLink

Windows Application

Gamelink is a platform for the creation, facilitating, and grading of algorithm-based coding competitions for the faculty of Software Engineering at UOIT. Students could create algorithms to play certain games and then compete agaist each other over the internet.

- Java JUnit Maven
- WebSockets UML